<resources>
    <string name="app_name">About Me</string>
    <string name="name_text">Shahin Alam</string>
    <string name="Bio">
    Is lemon water good for kidneys?
Lemon water is rich in sugars, vitamin C, vitamin B1, vitamin B2, niacin, and minerals such as calcium, phosphorus, and iron.

Drinking some lemon water every day can supplement the nutrients the body needs.

        New research also found that drinking lemon water can prevent the formation of kidney stones, which is very beneficial to kidney health.

After the minerals in the urine crystallize and accumulate inside the kidneys, kidney stones can occur.

Lemon water contains a lot of citric acid, which can inhibit mineral crystallization, thereby reducing the incidence of kidney stones.

In addition, lemon water is rich in vitamin C, 100 grams of lemon juice contains about 39 mg of vitamin C.

Vitamin C is a natural antioxidant, with anti-oxidation, anti-inflammatory, anti-viral, anti-bacterial and other functions.

        What are the benefits of drinking lemon water?
Lemon water is all the rage these days.

Many restaurants serve it routinely, and some people start their day with lemon water instead of coffee or tea. There’s no doubt lemons are great for adding citrus flavor to food and drinks, but are there any benefits to adding lemon juice to your water?

Much of the evidence supporting lemon water’s health benefits is anecdotal.

While lemons contain nutrients, like vitamin C and antioxidants, the nutritional value of a glass of lemon water depends on how much lemon juice it contains.

A glass of lemon water containing one 48 gram lemon, squeezed, contains:Trusted Source

10.6 calories
18.6 milligrams (mg) of vitamin C, or 21% of the Daily value (DV)
9.6 micrograms (mcg) of folate, or 2% of the DV
49.4 mg of potassium, or 1% of the DV
0.038 mg of iron, or  1% of the DV
0.01 mg of vitamin B-1, or 1% of the DV
0.01 mg of vitamin B-2, or 1% of the DV
0.06 mg of vitamin B-5, or 1% of the DV
Here’s how your body may benefit.

Promotes hydration
Making sure you’re drinking enough water every day is crucialTrusted Source for overall health — but not everyone likes the taste of plain water. Using lemon juice to add some flavor to your water may help you drink more.

Drinking water helps prevents dehydration, a condition that can cause:

brain fog
mood changes
overheating
constipation
kidney stones
According to the Institute of Medicine, general guidelines say women should get at least 91 ounces of water per day and men should get at least 125 ounces. This includes water from food and drinks.


Good source of Vitamin C
Citrus fruits like lemons contain vitamin C, a primary antioxidant that helps protect cells from damaging free radicals.

On top of that, vitamin C also plays a role in helping your body synthesize collagen, absorb iron, and produce hormones.

Additionally, not consuming enough vitamin C may cause symptoms, like:

increased susceptibility to infections
dryness of the mouth and eyes
dry skin
fatigue
insomnia
loosening of teeth

            </string>
    <string name="Content_Description">Image Not Found</string>

</resources>